Father God, we come before you today. We just ask that you be with us. We conduct this business with the city of Mayana for the community and its people. Father, we just allow us not to overlook this week, Father, for your sacrifice and your resurrection throughout this week. We thank you. We praise you and we love you.
Thank you.
I'm a special utility authority to issue its utility system and sales tax revenue note series 2026 in the aggregate principal amount of not to exceed $14 million, $200,000, waving competitive bidding and authorizing the note to be sold on a negotiated basis.
It's an executive or execution of a sales tax agreement by between City of Mayama, Oklahoma, and the authority pertaining to the year-to-year pledge of certain sales tax revenue approving an authorizing execution of indenture authorizing the issuance of securing the payment of the note, providing that the issuance and securing the payment of the note, providing that the organizational document creating the authority is subject to the provisions of the indenture.
Radifying and confirming a lease pertaining to the city's water, sanitary sewer, garbage, and electric systems, authorizing and directing the execution of the note and other documents related to the transaction, including professional services, agreements, and party agreement and containing other provisions relating there to.
So thank you all for tonight. This is something we've worked very, very hard for. This is actually the financing for Fiverr, or AMI leaders, and then some water plant work.
Tonight we have Chris Gander from B.O.K., we have Nate Ellis, and then we have Alan Brooks. He always has really good shoes on.
So they're here to kind of talk about everything. They help just get financing. The different quotes that we have in front of you guys.
We have some awesome financing. I mean, the looks like Simmons is the lowest. I mean, it's redeemable anytime, so we don't have a pre-payment penalty.
I mean, so it's like, we're pleased with the results. So I'll turn it over to them.
This one that Simmons Bank appears to us clearly be the best option, and times where it needs to be. The ability to pre-pay at a day time is really significant for two reasons.
I mean, if you had a funding that became a bail, you just want to pay the hell out of them. If you get that in the hole or in part, that's great.
The fact that the base option is, you know, a year from now, two years from now, it's a waste block.
I wonder if this is why some of you have heard me as an excuse to actually say the same thing from my life potentially.
I'm not going to get you to do that big here. It's a place of building that is very, very helpful for all the places.
There's even a place that will go down two or three years from now. I mean, for a year and a half, there's 15 years out of that plan.
I mean, they say, in theory, we can get less ratings right, because it's 12 years, and it's at that point, 15 years.
So again, we will monitor that by knowing full of places.
The crystal, the good job of staying after a year is financial institutions.
It's a positive reflection of financial situation.
I mean, you've had Tom's debt coverage. You've had free cash flow that's pledged to this transaction,
one with your father, a outstanding debt, to put you in an area of most other communities.
I mean, it's a very strong financial position, and you can sort of leave obviously
from that historical standpoint in your audience, or you can stay on top of things financially.
And that is what it's like to figure out.
I mean, the crystal urges tail on trying to get this, but if financials didn't support that, you wouldn't have been very successful.
So having said that, I think the financial situation certainly made these transactions easier.
The resolution, which I would like to use initially, popularizes the execution of various documents.
This transaction is going to be equally secure, but it's not stated on that.
You have your utility revenues, in a two-centre-centre-centre-centre pledge, this debt will be fully secured with that debt.
That's just what pledge of revenue is.
If you've authorized a amount of documents in your transaction, assuming you've heard this exceedingly,
the approval of the resolution would be approved, the resolution, and accept the bid for savings bank.
And we would have that in the likes of the resolution, assuming you've approved that,
assuming you've gotten the fact that closing transactions are about 10.
This is the two.
Yeah, this is the one that was closing that.
So once you make your decision, seeing that you put this in position, send that graph on documents,
we'll be sending those to this fund in your city attorney, we'll be sending them to the bank,
and there are counsels.
Obviously, here is really much, but that was strong.
We've got some of the documents down the line because most of the money is from the city's crash, some of the documents in the bank.
So we've got to go ahead and start them.
But if we're very pleased, we'll be happy to answer any questions that you might have.
I just got one thing to say.
I'm not going to say anything about the rights because it's pretty self-explanatory.
It doesn't seem like the best bid, but we give this question a lot about waiting competitive bidding,
and that would bring you bids, things like countertune.
So just to the point of, if you're wondering that, that's kind of an official competitive bidding process.
There's a state-required way when selling general litigation on the property tax bonds.
So it's kind of a formality that we say that, even though realistically, we send these packets out to lots of banks,
and we did go through competitive processes.
You said you'd have to go right to that.
That's all I have to add.
The only question I have was in Section 6, the lease dates.
It's the only question that I had were in Section 6, the lease dates.
Those are the dates of the existing lease that's in place.
So you have a given existing lease that was done in 1981.
It has a 50-year term of automatic renewal, and for so long, his debt is outstanding.
That lease relates to the water sewer, electric, and carbon systems.
The city owns the systems.
They lease them over to the public trust, especially utility authority.
They can have those revenues available to pledge that is collateral for the debt.
We might have wanted to go in and update that to a vintage 2026 document,
except you have bonds outstanding, and so we really can't do that without getting involved.
It's just a ratification that existing documents have been placed in.
So in order to maintain the ability to repay this note at the schedule,
what does our take rate have to be?
Well, you know, because it's not our business for A and I.
Right now, our electrical already covered it.
I mean, we've kind of like carved out a place in our electric to pay the debt.
I mean, the hope is, you know, three years, three years, four, that we have enough take rate.
It'll take over this payment.
Okay, so we're not relying on take rate for...
No, sorry.
Okay, perfect. Thanks for the clarity.
And those revenues are not played.
The fiber revenues are not played.
Yeah.
At this time, it's a lot better.
No, then you can't use the fiber.
It's not played well.
Yeah.
I mean, other communities in your situation, if this fiber system gets up, becomes mature,
it's comparatively producing.
There's some future we can add to your bond with the fiber revenues.
At this point, there will raise more questions than that.
That's fair.
Thanks.
And if you just need to kind of raise a question, we don't know what that paper would be.
Crystal, thank you for familiarize yourself with all of this.
I have.
I've learned a lot during this process.
Because these guys have been very beneficial for me.
Not only just teaching me the past stuff, but also the present on how all this stuff works.
And I don't think it can work.
I know, too.
I want to say thank you to your team.
I know we met time.
I met with you guys a year and a half ago.
Tulsa.
At a conference.
And had a great talk about this project.
The thing Tyler and the city staff for staying on this and bringing this to fruition.
Missed you.
You've been involved.
So everybody's been involved.
Thank you.
This is going to change things for our community.
It's going to change one a good way.
It's going to change things for a long time inside the city, inside the city hall.
So I appreciate everybody's efforts to finally bring this to us today.
And I'll close this chapter and get rolling on it.
So, and you know, we met with someone yesterday that we were talking about this project,
and about borrowing the money to do this.
And they said, well, we could probably loan you the money.
And Tyler asked him kind of what rate.
And he said, well, what rate did you come before?
And he said, well, we were in the forest before.
And he said, oh, yeah, you're never going to get that.
And he's got to walk in the day with the 4th floor.
And it was like, wow.
Plus, with any kind of payoff, that's an added bonus that we weren't expecting.
So, great job by everybody.
With that, I'd make a motion to approve the resolution.
I will second.
All right.
Thank you.
This meeting will now be continued from Council Chamber.
It's a staff room.
The purpose of executive session.
The completion of the special meeting of the Monocity Council.
Thank you.
All right.